Nobody wants another old white bald guy
in a blue suit and Louis Vuitton
sneakers trying to convince you of a
version of the world that you know in
your heart is wrong. Think the world is
sick of that. And to be honest,
everything that you see around you was
invented and made by someone no greater
than you. And the notion that there are
some more important people than others
that are in the White House that decide
how much money should be worth to all of
us is a bunch of crap. The US government
for all intents and purposes in
practical terms is broke. What are the
different ways governments can spend
money? I think Bitcoin is the best
expression of currency debasement. It's
the best way to short the dollar. We're
saying, "Hey, China, take a bunch of
your profits and give it to us." So,
you're making less and we're making
more. That's a way to create more
balance. China will then have less trade
surplus to dump into the NASDAQ, to dump
into the stock market, to dump into nice
real estate. It will allow the financial
assets in America and the real estate
and the farmland to become more
affordable for the lower class. When you
say all these stocks being more
affordable, that means the market needs
to go down. Yeah. The notion that
utility is to provide something like the
dollar is the most widely used utility
token in the world. It has 6 billion
daily active users. Yet none of us are
using it to build and store wealth. So
why would I own Ethereum to build or
store wealth?
Tell us about that. I just got out of
college like here.
[Music]
We're back at the Bitcoin Las Vegas
Conference, the biggest Bitcoin
conference in the world. And joining us
today is Jack Mer, CEO of Strike and
co-founder and CEO of 21 Capital. I'm
David Lynn, Bonnie Jay, and we've had
the pleasure, both of us, of
interviewing you as soon as news came
out on 20 of 21 Cap. So, congrats. Uh 21
is doing great. We'll get updates on 21.
We'll get updates on strike. So, thank
you for being the first law form
interview uh for us. So, people can
check out that interview for the first
update. Links down below. I want to get
your personal story to becoming a
Bitcoiner. So your mother set up a
series of meetings for you or not just
for you but just in general. You were
there. You met who you believe to be the
goat y of Bitcoin Antonopoulos. Y tell
us about that meeting. Why that changed
your life. Yes. Well, first of all,
thanks for having me. I'm a fan of you
both. You guys should know that. Nice to
be here in person. Um yeah, my Bitcoin
story. My dad got me into Bitcoin. He
got me and my stepmother into Bitcoin.
So, he registered the Bitcoin mom
Twitter handle for my stepmom. And I had
just dropped out of college and he was
like, "Hey, listen here, buddy. I just
lost about 30 grand sending you to
school and you didn't learn anything, so
you're going to get into this Bitcoin
thing with me whether you like it or
not." And it turned out I liked it a
lot. And the story you're referencing,
my stepmom started the very first
Bitcoin meetup in Chicago. It was at my
house. I came home from coding boot camp
and Andreas Antonopoulos was in my
living room and with I don't know seven
or eight other people and saying a lot
of what we talk about on this podcast
talking about how Bitcoin can empower
humanity and how it is a continuation of
the human story of engineering a better
world and I was like whoa who's this guy
and I took my backpack off and I sat
there and I listened and then 13 years
later here I am David talking to you
your dad was an OG Bitcoiner so he
worked worked at the uh well he you can
give us his background but he was a
futures broker and he bought Bitcoin I
believe 2010 2013 I wish he bought it in
2010 yeah late 2012 late 20120 yeah but
like what what got him into it because
he came from Trafi obviously um well so
my grandfather was the youngest ever
chairman of the Chicago Board of Trade
he actually signed the uh check to start
the SIBO and and now there's the CME as
well um but very early pioneer in what I
would describe the difference between
Chicago and New York. You know, New
York, um, you know, us Chicago market
folks have sometimes not the nicest
thing to say about Wall Street culture.
Wall Street's great. They're necessary
financial capital markets of the world,
but you know, that's Wolf of Wall
Street, penny stocks, insider trading.
Chicago, what my grandfather helped
pioneer was the agriculture commodity
derivatives market. This was risk
transfer for the commodities that you
and I eat. Yeah. Corn, wheat, soybeans.
Is how do we take the risk away from the
corn farmer that's got to produce the
corn and transfer that risk into an
efficient market and build products like
a futures contract or an options
contract. And so very much pioneered
that. That's a Midwestern financial
market. That's the Chicago markets. My
favorite story about my grandfather is
the Hunt brothers who went on to try and
corner the silver market. They tried to
corner that market in Chicago. My
grandfather was the chairman at the time
and he said, "You're not going to do
unethical financial market activity
here. If you want to pull off that
nonsense, you got to go to New York." So
they did. But Chicago is very cultured,
ethical, principled and they had built a
lot of these markets with their hands
and they actually not only my father but
Don Wilson, Cumberland, DRW, a lot of
those jump trading, a lot of these
Chicago prop firms, trading firms, high
frequency firms got Bitcoin first. And
so it was around then when they all
everyone in Chicago was building
positions 2013 and I had just dropped
out of college. Um, if I have a minute
more, I'll tell you guys my favorite.
You got all the time in the world for
us. So, my favorite story of my father
when Bitcoin really clicked for us and
for him was after Silk Road was busted.
And it's not it's a counterintuitive
story, but I love telling it because so
Silk Road, for those that don't know,
the famed uh dark web drug marketplace,
right? and it was the first supposed
free market and you could buy and sell
all sorts of drugs and had access to
total human free trade globally and it
used Bitcoin as an anonymous currency
that credit card networks couldn't stop.
Now, the reason that this was such an
aha moment for my dad and he sat me down
and explained it to me is like the
government was able to shut down Silk
Road but not through Bitcoin.
They tried to censor the currency. They
tried to shut down the Bitcoin network.
They tried to control it and they
couldn't. They shut down Silk Road
because they found the server. And so
while everyone was mistaking this story
as a drug bust, I saw it as a real proof
of concept that the FBI, the CIA, the US
government could not, if their life
depended on it, stop this thing. And if
they couldn't do it now, they're not
going to be able to do it later. And
that means there's only going to be 21
million. And it was after that moment
where we were like, "Oh crap." And since
then, it's been like all hands on deck,
get as much as you can, digital gold
rush. That was the first real proof of
concept where we realized like whoa um
this thing cannot be changed by anyone.
Doesn't matter how powerful you are. And
there were stories like that. Shortly
after that was the Cypress crisis in
Greece and Bitcoin reacted really
favorably during that crisis. And we had
seen these smaller but meaningful
iterations of Bitcoin facing adversity
and really powerful powerful whether it
was governments or agencies and no one
can get in its way. And so that was a
lot of my I was 18. That was my my
Bitcoin journey. But you come from
Treadfi family. So before Bitcoin, you
probably trusted the market and the old
financial system because that's what we
were taught kind of. I actually I know
that that probably seems uh reasonable,
but it's not true. Um the way my dad
described to me is Bitcoin is the best
expression of currency debasement. It's
the best way to short the dollar. He's
always talked to me about this portfolio
that he's been trying to build which is
short dollar. He owns historically real
estate is a way of short dollar exchange
stock. So owning the CME stock, owning
the Chicago Board o of trade stock. The
reason that that is short dollar is
because if you live in a currency
debasement era, everyone's a speculator
whether they know it or not. So
exchanges are great businesses because
everyone needs to buy a stock, buy a
bond, buy something to avoid getting
debased and things inflated out of their
life. And now Bitcoin and he's always
described to me as building a short
dollar portfolio because these guys,
these old finance guys, they lived
through the divorce of the gold
standard. They lived through the 2008
financial crisis. So anyone really in
tune in financial markets has seen the
government get too big, seen regulators
step in and bias Wall Street, bail out
banks. And so yes, I come from
traditional financial markets, but the
financial markets my grandfather was
founding were traditionally freer
markets, far lesser sized government. We
were still on a gold standard. And so I
think a lot of the latest iteration of
the financial system today, I would say
some of the Chicago guys have taken
personally. And that's why they've taken
an akin to Bitcoin of finally I got
something that a regulator can't walk
into my office and debase and print more
of and take out of my hands. You were
talking about printing money yesterday
on your live stream. And when a regular
person hear money printing, they think
of this physical money being print, but
it's not. Break it down for us. What are
the different ways governments can print
money? Yeah. Well, so I think um for the
layman's person on the street, what they
need to understand is the United States
as the world reserve currency issuer
structurally has to operate in what's
called a deficit. So if you were to
think of the US as a business operating
trade, it posts huge losses. It does it
unprofitably. So if you have a business
that's constantly losing money, how does
it afford its bills? Well, it needs
people to lend it money to continue to
perpetuate its services. So the
government actually gets money lent to
it in the form of these bonds,
treasuries market. And so when you buy a
10-year, you're actually lending money
to the government and they're paying you
an interest for the money that you're
giving them so that they can continue to
finance and operate the US government.
And the biggest problem that the US
government has right now is that no
one's willing to lend it money anymore.
Right? The deal was, hey, China, we'll
allow you guys to operate in this trade
surplus, which has now reached a
trillion dollars annually. You will take
then that cash flow. You don't reinvest
it back into your economy because it'll
strengthen your local currency. What you
need to do is buy dollar-based assets.
The dollar based assets we want you to
buy are these treasuries. So, we're
going to allow you to operate in this
surplus. We're going to print you this
money and give it to you. In return,
you're going to lend it back to us. But,
um, that deal is long gone, especially
after the 2008 financial crisis. China
and other trade partners like screw
this. I'm not keeping my purchasing
power by holding the dollar and and
buying these treasuries. And so what the
US government and specifically the
Treasury Secretary whether it's
Secretary Yelen now Bessent it doesn't
matter we're living in a fiscal dominant
era where the Treasury has to find a way
for the US government to sustain itself
and finance itself given that no one
wants to lend to it. So it's an
increasing amount of debt. The US
government for all intents and purposes
in practical terms is broke. It needs
someone to lend it money to keep going
and it can't find those lenders. So an
example of printing money without
actually printing the currency as you
mentioned is like the change of the
supplemental leverage ratio where banks
can use unlimited amounts of leverage to
buy bonds which is lend the government
money. So unlimited amounts of leverage
that is establishing buying power with
currency that you don't actually have
like you know leverage if you have
unlimited amount of leverage you're
allowed to borrow as much money without
any physical constraints without posting
any collateral without having to prove
the work to access the leverage in the
first place. So things like treasury
buybacks, things like the supplemental
leverage ratio, things like bringing
Freddy Mack in or Freddy May and Freddy
Mack out of a government control and as
a private business. Again, these are all
sneakier ways to quote unquote print
money which is provide liquidity to the
market specifically to help the
treasuries market specifically to find
dollars that will lend to the United
States to allow them to continue to
finance themselves. Um, how does Terara
fit in this picture or is it a complete
different story? No, no, not at all. The
So, the problem and by the way, this is
bipartisan. I know that people associate
not only Bitcoin but a lot of economic
efforts as Republican, Democrat, left,
right. Um, the bipartisan effort is this
is that the US deficits are
unsustainable.
The reason and we had talked about this
on our our last show is this goes all
the way back to the world wars in that
post world wars US took on the world
reserve currency issuer and as we
mentioned within that you take on
deficits and you allow other countries
to produce things for you. So you print
dollars and you ship those dollars out.
In return, you get food, oil, energy, my
iPhone, this microphone, probably not
produced here in the United States of
America. What does that do to your
country? Well, one, it disables your
ability to produce anything because
you've delegated and outsourced making
phones, microphones, food, energy, gas,
all of that to other trade partners
throughout the world. It also destroys
your middle class because as everyone
else gets a trade surplus and they
reinvest that capital back into
dollar-based assets, they're buying the
stocks, they're buying the real estate,
they're buying the farmland, and so
asset holders are getting perpetually
wealthier through some type of
artificial strength in dollarand dollar
based assets because China's trade
surplus is being poured right back into
the Mag 7, into Manhattan pen houses,
into the most pristine farmland. And so
the ultra rich are getting wealthier and
the ultra poor are exceedingly getting
further away from being able to acquire
the life that they want to live. So this
is bipartisan in America is that this
isn't sustainable? And the real question
that no one's saying out loud is is
being the world reserve currency
actually in our interest anymore? And
it's gotten so bad that it's become a
national security threat. So you can
debate whether this has eroded the
middle class, whether this has eroded
our ability to manufacture stuff. But to
look at a stat to say close to 80% of US
weapons need China to help produce. Now
it's a national security threat. Now it
doesn't matter what you think about
economics. It doesn't matter what you
think about the dollar. This is national
security. And that's where we are as a
country. Tariffs are a way to try and
bring back balance. Bring back balance
meaning heightening our deficits so that
we're not losing as much money and
shrinking China's surplus. So, in very
layman's terms, we're saying, "Hey,
China, take a bunch of your profits and
give it to us." So, you're making less
and we're making more. That's a way to
create more balance. China will then
have less trade surplus to dump into the
NASDAQ, to dump into the stock market,
to dump into nice real estate. It'll
allow the financial assets in America
and the real estate and the farmland to
become more affordable for the lower
class, right? And and start to fix some
of these problems. Now, Trump has since
pivoted greatly. Tariffs didn't work.
They're now on to capital controls which
achieve a similar thing. But at the end
of the day, it's we're trying to unwind
from an old monetary regime which was
set up after the world wars which was
America is going to be the world reserve
currency because they have the most gold
because they had the strongest
manufacturing base. But if you compound
this over a hundred years, it's very
irrational, unnatural economic behavior.
You cannot print pieces of paper and
ship them all over the world to get real
stuff in return. Eventually people don't
want your paper anymore. Eventually
people don't want to lend you money
anymore. Eventually, China owns. It's
It's fun in games when China's like,
"Sure, we'll run this trade surplus and
buy the 10-year Treasury, but it's not
that funny when China's like, "Sure,
we'll make a trillion dollars a year off
you, and then we own Apple, we own
Google, we own the nicest houses, we own
all the farmland." Then it's not that
funny. Um, so that's where we are today.
And the question now is what next? When
you say all these stocks being more
affordable, that means the mar the the
market needs to go down. Yeah. And is
that a good thing? I think so. Listen,
you know, I can fix the US's problem in
give me a day. The problem is the
currency. Now, how politically palatable
is the solution? That's what we're
struggling with and what Trump has to
figure out. But the reality is, if you
really wanted to solve the problem, the
problem is the currency. The dollar is
artificially strong because of its world
reserve status. Dollar-based assets are
reserve status. meaning we print
dollars, we ship them all over the
world. Countries give us other stuff in
return. Now they have all these dollars.
They have to do something with the
dollars. They cannot reinvest them
locally. It'll ruin their export
business. So they puke them back into
America. So American exceptionalism and
a really strong NASDAQ that never goes
down has been entirely funded by
countries like China. And so if Trump's
new mandate, which the American first
investment policy, which came out in
February, Trump said basically take your
money and go home. Get out of the
market. when you saw dollar down, bonds
down, uh stocks down, usually it's
stocks down, but bonds do well because
it's a flight to safety, right? Dollar
down, stocks down, bonds down. What does
that mean? That means America's or
capital's leaving the country. That
means money's leaving America. Trump's
mandate to China and other trade
partners is get your money out of the
country. These things need the dollar
has to get weaker. Now, Scott Besson and
Trump won't say we want a weaker dollar.
What will they say? China needs to
strengthen their currency. We need to
find some equilibrium. They're using
words that, you know, that's not the
Trump the Trump brand isn't weak, right?
So, he will never say, "I need a weaker
dollar and we need to question the
reserve status of the dollar." He would
never say that. But that's what we're
talking about. I can fix this problem by
saying, "We're going back on a gold
bitcoin standard. We're going to all
your dollars are redeemable for either
gold or bitcoin, and we're not the world
reserve currency anymore. We're going to
settle in a neutral reserve asset."
Boom. China. I think if you look at the
amount of gold China imported over the
last year versus their trillion dollar
trade surplus, if if an ounce of gold
was worth $20,000, China ran budget
neutral. So, in my opinion, the way to
solve this is move back to neutral
reserve asset. No one should be the
world reserve currency issuer because
it's a death curse. There's the Triffin
dilemma. You can't have a middle class.
You can't manufacture. You run in
deficits. You create wealth gaps. You
destroy the fabric of your country. And
so, that's the solution. The question
is, can they get away with it in a way
that's politically palatable that um
doesn't cause civil unrest in the
country? That's that's the reality we're
living through right now. They can tax
the foreigners. I heard that if you tax
foreign um investment in US 2%, then the
locals don't need to pay income tax.
Yeah. So, what they're trying to do, so
again, you're you're trying to correct
this global imbalance. And if tariffs
aren't going to work, which clearly
they're not, and it was too aggressive.
And I I think what the Trump
administration didn't realize is they
didn't have as much leverage as they
thought, one week after liberation day,
where as an American I felt oh so
liberated, uh the Treasury market
malfunctioned and fell apart and
financial authorities had to step in.
And so that is when Bessant, Trump,
Powell realized they don't have the
leverage in negotiations in a trade war
with China that they thought they did.
And you saw this extreme pivot where
it's like, oh, we put on a pause. Let's
give it 90 days. And now the pivot is to
capital controls. And what capital
controls are is it's trying to achieve
effectively the same thing. Trump has
flirted with a 30% withholding tax on
foreigners assets. Meaning, if you do
own Google stock, if you do own
luxurious real estate in America, if you
own farmland, we're going to tax you
30%. Or there's a proposal like you
mentioned 2%. Whatever it is, it's it's
discouraging foreign capital. If you saw
Harvard recently came out with a a press
release that hit the wire that said,
"We're not allowing foreigners to enroll
students in and pay us anymore." Well,
that's Trump's administration blocking
them and now Harvard suing them back.
Yeah. Yes. So, meaning foreign capital
isn't even good for an education
anymore. That is take get your money out
of our country. And this is a way of
saying yes, you have a surplus of
dollars, but they are no longer good
here. By the way, those are fighting
words. You cannot print and give me a
trillion dollars and not allow me to put
them anywhere. If what you're saying is
a functionally you have to put them in
the 10-year Treasury, but Treasury Scott
Besson is saying, "My focus right now is
to make sure GDP is growing faster than
the debt." That's a very fancy way of
saying in real terms rates are negative.
You're not going to retain purchasing
power holding the 10-year. And by the
way, if you own all these other assets,
I'm going to tax the heck out of you.
But the one thing Trump did not tariff
gold. The one thing he's made sure to
set a strategic reserve for and promote
Bitcoin. And so to me, in so many words,
he's saying, "Stop buying our stocks.
Stop buying our land. Stop buying our
real estate. Stop artificially
strengthening the dollar. stop
artificially strengthening assets in
this country. By the way, you could buy
the 10-year, but we're actually gonna
allow the banking system to highly lever
themselves to solve that problem. I
wouldn't own it. You'll be negative in
real terms. Buy gold, buy Bitcoin. And
then I think at some point in this
administration, over the next 5 years,
we will see a transition where you'll
start seeing global trade settled or at
least priced in an asset that isn't the
dollar. Well, let's shift gears now and
talk about the banking sector. Last time
you were on our show, we had asked you
about when traditional financial
institutions like banks would catch up
to strike would catch up to um you know
your company about uh in regards to
transactioning in bitcoin. Now JP Morgan
since then JP Morgan chief Jamie Diamond
has issued a statement and I quote he
says we are going to allow you to buy it
quoting Diamond he said it referring to
Bitcoin we're not going to custody it.
We're going to put it in statements for
clients. So a little step towards that
direction. What is the larger trend? I
think this is really exciting. Um I
think a lot of the financial services
innovation for our industry has lived
outside of the United States of America
because I think businesses like Coinbase
and Kraken have lived within this sort
of regulatory moat where if you think
about it the most innovative product
that makes the most money in our space
for 10 years running is just buying
Bitcoin. There is there has no one's
figured out lending which we could talk
about which I'm trying to do. No one has
figured out deeply embedded financial
services that add functional utility to
the asset class because I don't think
these businesses have had to. They've
Coinbase cracking these businesses which
are you know it's not personal it's all
business but they've had really cozy
positions that no one can compete with
them. It takes a lot of license a lot of
capital a lot of friends in Washington
DC. So I think this is all good is that
the industry is starting to see more
domestic competition. I think it's
great. Like, you know, Coinbase has been
charging people to buy Bitcoin 4 and
a.5% for 10 years. If Jamie Diamond
starts allowing you to buy Bitcoin out
of your Chase account for a fraction of
a basis point, I'm sure Coinbase is
going to have to start innovating. So, I
view it as, you know, competition breeds
innovation. Um, at Strike personally,
you know, we're prepared for that.
That's why we've launched global
products. That's why we've gotten into
lending. We want to continue to lead as
a financial services provider to provide
functional utility to Bitcoiners. But I
see it as America catching up as far as
innovation. The broader trend, like I I
really I really urge the United States
of America to do for Bitcoin what they
did with the internet. With the
internet, they really just said, "Hey,
listen, don't harm people. Don't steal
from people. Besides that, no rules.
Create the future." And we did. Are you
surprised though that he said like he's
not going to custody it? Um, no. Uh, I
think they'll get there. Uh, I do think
that there's just so much bureaucracy
that lives. I mean, at Strike, we have
less than 100 employees, and one of the
main reasons is it allows us to move
fast, have the culture we want. We don't
get attracted to the notion of having a
big office with a ton of people. Um, and
so I think there's so much bureaucracy.
These things move slower than you think.
It might take a decade for Chase Bank to
fully figure out how Bitcoin works, what
their strategy is to offer a slew of
vertical financial services. But the
fact that they can come out and say,
"We're interested and we're going to
start with the one that everyone loves,
which is buying it." I think that's huge
because it sends a signal to an industry
that hasn't had to really compete that
much. And so, we're all going to have to
innovate a lot. And I'm excited about
that. On Stripe loans, you give users a
24 hours heads up to add more
collateral. Yeah. Um,
was this from a user's feedback? what
you know where do people usually mess up
during a crash or a dip or a correction?
Yeah. So for our lending so our lending
product allows you to borrow against
Bitcoin. So it's like a home equity
loan. You own an asset that's scarce and
desirable. You don't want to sell it.
Bitcoin for example is compounding at
over 60% a year on average over the last
10 years. So you don't want to get rid
of that unless you have to. So what if
you can get borrow some cash against it
and that's the product that we're
offering. And we offer the product at
50% LTV, which is important, meaning you
can only take half of the value out of
the Bitcoin in cash. We do that because
the asset's so volatile and we're trying
to protect customers. If I let you take
100% in cash out and then Bitcoin dipped
a little bit, well, then you're
underwater. And so you start at 50% LTV
and as that LTV grows towards 100%, we
start to issue you alerts and say, "Hey,
you might want to pay attention." And
then at some point, what we call a
margin call is, hey, you've reached a
level that is too scary for us and you
have 24 hours to just deposit a little
bit more Bitcoin. And we give those
instructions. And again, this is just
because we aren't in the business of our
customers don't really speculate. We do
offer buy and sell, but we're
predominantly buy side. Our customers,
our customers we consider Bitcoiners,
and you know, we aren't in the business
of highly speculative trading options.
That's not us. um these are financial
services and we don't want to liquidate
customers and a lot of our customers are
taking loans out to start a business to
finance a medical emergency to put a
down payment on a home to do things that
are good for the world and that you know
I think that's great and and so the
product is built around trying to
protect them um in what is a highly
volatile asset but we've talked about on
the show volatility breeds performance
and so if you want the performance
Bitcoin gives you you have to find a way
to deal with the volatility and so in
the product we do our
Paint me this future where we just use
Bitcoin in our everyday lives. What
would it look like? I could tell you
about my everyday life. Go ahead. So I
don't own any dollars. You guys know
that. You know what's funny, David? Uh
one of the most famed clips. Sometimes
I'll open my Instagram account and I'll
just see my face of me on your show
talking about the fact that I don't own
any dollars. So I appreciate that clip.
Um but we've talked about this. I don't
own any dollars. The way I do it is I
get my paychecks direct deposited and
converted to Bitcoin. I spend on credit
cards. So, the credit card is a great
product because I get to spend dollars
without ever h having to own them. Uh,
and then I use the lending product. So,
the way I use it personally is I borrow
against my Bitcoin to avoid having to
sell it. I borrow maybe anywhere between
like 1 to 5% of my total stack. So, you
know, short-term cash expenses, but then
in that way, I'm getting paid in
Bitcoin. I'm spending on credit. And
then to finance, I have to pay my credit
card bill. I have to pay my HOA. I have
to pay my taxes. And when I need cash, I
just borrow against my Bitcoin, get the
cash. The way our our lending product
has two forms and facets. One is monthly
interest payments like a traditional
loan. The other is what we call payment
at maturity. So, you don't actually pay
us monthly. you owe us the principal
plus the interest at the end of the
term. So every year and so what I do is
I take out this rolling loan where when
I need cash and then at the end of the
year I take out a new loan, pay off the
existing loan and then I keep going. And
obviously I only borrow against a small
amount of my Bitcoin stack because if
Bitcoin dips I can go add more
collateral. I'm never in a position in
my life where I'm overlevered and I need
Bitcoin to be a certain price or else my
life falls apart. But I now have
established a life where I get paid in
Bitcoin. I only hold Bitcoin. I never
have to sell my Bitcoin. And I just,
yes, the loan is whatever 8 9 10 11% but
Bitcoin's going up 50 60% on average.
And so as long as it's Kagger is above
the interest rate to borrow, then uh I'm
running like a perpetual short dollar
trade and it feels pretty good. Yeah. So
that would that would necessitate the
interest rate staying low. If it if if
let's say we get a return to the 80s for
example, we get double digit 10ear
yield, would that change your life?
Um, if the 10-year yield went to 80%,
I think Bitcoin would probably be worth
like a million. All right. And uh
there's a headline right there. Yeah, I
would uh I would I would happily take
that. Yeah. I mean, so, um, the the most
difficult thing about sourcing capital
for Bitcoiners to borrow against their
Bitcoin is if you understand Bitcoin,
you'd rather just own it and get the 60%
KAGER than any fixed rate. Um, but we've
been able to do that and source that
capital. And if the rate goes up, I
mean, really, at the end of the day, if
you have a long-term time horizon, as
long as the compound annual growth rate
of the asset is over the cost to borrow
it, um, it's a mathematically a good
idea. And so that gap, so part of the
announcement that I'm here to make at
the conference is we're gonna be able to
offer singledigit loans of material size
up to a billion dollars. So you know,
even the president of Al Salvador wanted
a loan against their Bitcoin. I could
finance that. And at a single digit and
we're getting closer and closer to
mortgage rates and and really what's the
collateral they have to post? Bitcoin.
Okay, that's it. And and the coolest
part about the product, no credit
checks. You know, one one of our early
customers called me and said, "Hey, you
know, this is where I went to school.
Trust me, I'm a good guy. I'm married."
Said, "No, no, man. You're
misunderstanding the product." Bitcoin
is like liquid land. It's digital land.
You just deposit into the app and you
just take the cash out and immediately
put it in your Chase account. Like, I
don't need to approve you for anything.
It's the quickest way a business could
get a multi-million dollar loan. And so
you deposit Bitcoin into the app, you
tell me how much cash you want. It's
immediately in your Chase account in
seven seconds, and you go live your
life. And it's such a it's such a
mind-boggling product that you can own
the best performing thing with the the
thing that I think people misunderstand
like a Peter Schiff is they say Bitcoin
has no cash flow. Yeah. Right. So like
like a home equity loan. Yeah. But I can
rent it out on Airbnb and pay the
interest that way. You know, I would
make the argument that every single
asset has cash flow. There's two forms
of cash flow. There's issuer cash flow,
like a bond has cash flow because the
issuer is paying you interest, right?
But then there's seller cash flow where
Bitcoin has cash flow. I just have to
sell it to get the cash. If I bought a
Bitcoin for $50 and it's $100,000 now, I
could sell it for $100,000. I get
$100,000 worth of cash flow. The problem
with assets that you own, like the house
you live in or Bitcoin, you have to sell
the asset to get the cash. What if I can
provide you liquidity for your Bitcoin
without having to sell it? That's the
unlock. And what you realize is um the
VOC that ran global trade in the 600s
did this against their ships in their
land. This is how Manhattan was built.
Early Manhattan real estate and land, no
one sold it when they had a medical
emergency or when they wanted to get
married. They borrowed against it when
they wanted to build a bar on their
land. This is what, you know, Tesla put
restrictions on how much Elon Musk could
borrow against his shares because he
doesn't own a pile of dollars. So the
way if you have scarce desirable assets
and you can afford to keep them then
find a way to get liquidity by borrowing
against them and bitcoin has yet to have
this market in a reliable way and these
are the type of financial services that
I think competition breeds this level of
innovation of like if you want to add to
bitcoin's utility this to us at strike
was just like a very obvious way
if I am this bitcoin treasury company
and I want to deposit my bitcoin on your
platform form and take out you know loan
and buy more Bitcoin. I want to know
what you do with my Bitcoin. Uh nothing
which is a very important piece of the
product. So traditionally other folks in
the Bitcoin space what they would do is
they would get deposits and then they
would go lend those out or go and
reinvest those like that's what Sam
Bakerman Freed did and you blow up that
way. For us there's no yield. There's no
one of the biggest parts of the product
is Strike is an immensely profitable
company. We're small. We're lean, we're
focused, we're not, you know, going on
cruises with Bill Clinton or whatever
that kid was doing at the time. It's
here's the product. You deposit Bitcoin,
it sits right here on the blockchain.
And actually in a future iteration
that's coming out in a month or two is
where you can see it. Part of the beauty
of Bitcoin is the cryptographic proof.
And so you deposit the Bitcoin, it sits
right here. It never moves. It's your
collateral for the duration of your
loan. And we make money just on the
interest. And there's no yield. There's
no fancy business. We're not this
massive company that's stretched thin
between 300 different coins. We are very
good at selling ethical, high
functioning Bitcoin financial services.
And that's one of the many reasons we're
very, very different than something
that's existed before is keep it simple.
Have you ever been interested in any
altcoins? No. Never. Never. That's
interesting because the normal journey
of a person getting into crypto would
be, hey, I learned about Bitcoin and
then there was this shinier thing for
the moment and then I'm distracted. But
why is yours not like that? Well, I
think if you put yourself back into the
time where I was coming home to my
living room to Andreas Antonopoulos and
back in those days, that's when all of
those alt coins were being created. So,
like, think about joining Bitcoin before
Ethereum existed. I was there when
Vitalic Vitalik sold some pre-sale ETH
to my stepmom at a conference like this.
Vitalic was like, "Hi, my name's Vitalic
and I'm working on this new project.
Would you want to support us by buying
some Ethereum?" And my stepmom was like,
"Sure, sweetie. You seem like a nice
kid." And that that's a true story. And
so when I I got to kind of before these
things got so big and had such marketing
engines behind them and all these
narratives of DeFi or NFTTS or ICOs or
whatever next load of crap, I was there
and I saw that these things weren't
technically sound. I didn't understand
the value acrruel narrative like the
notion that utility is to provide
something like the dollar is the most
widely used utility token in the world.
It has six billion daily active users.
Yet none of us are using it to build and
store wealth. So why would I own
Ethereum to build or store wealth? So I
just saw them all be created. Are you
Did you just mean to say every single
util piece of utility built on alts can
be built on the dollar? No, my point is
that the rhetoric that you hear is well
these things are going to become so
useful to society, right? That that's
why the price is going to go up is
because they're so useful. But you know
the dollar is really useful to the world
but its price doesn't necessarily go up
in my opinion being a store of value.
It's I mean a price in any market is
simply a function of supply and demand.
And so if you build something with a
restrictive supply and you allow the
demand to compete in a free market
that's what drives price up. And so this
notion that Ethereum it was always going
to be the world computer or going to be
the art platform of the world or I've
been I David I've been around for all of
them. None of them have ever come true.
But again I I struggle to find what is
the value of cruel narrative outside of
rampant speculation as we live through
very active debasement of the world
reserve currency. Um so outside of that
I still don't understand the narrative
and I wouldn't be surprised if Tether
flipped Ethereum's market cap at this
point. Um, I I think it's flipped every
other altcoin besides Ethereum. So,
well, let's uh let's talk about that.
That was a smooth transition, brother.
That's why you're a professional. You
You guys feel the inspiration. 21, give
us an update on 21. Paulo's a co-founder
along with SoftBank, Bitfinex. Yeah. Uh,
so I mean, we're doing great. Uh, I had
mentioned on the show, we're in what's
called the approval process. So, we
filed. That is going along swimmingly.
Just making sure that everyone who needs
to know what we do and why we do it
does. Uh, the most exciting update that
I have for you guys on the show is our
proof of reserves. So, I believe we'll
be the largest um company, especially
Bitcoin Treasury company to provide such
proof that we own the assets that we
claim we do. Um, we do this very simply
by I mean right now our Bitcoin is held
at Tether as an escrow. So once the
transaction is closed, it will be solely
owned by 21. But as we're in this
approval process, there's a bit of an
escrow. But we wanted to publish that
escrow and show the Bitcoin community
that we have the assets. We have been
buying the Bitcoin. We have the assets
we say we do. We have over 31,000 coins
already. Upon closing, we'll have what
we believe to be over 42,000 Bitcoin.
And uh I think it builds trust. Why
Tether? Why not Circle, for example?
Um, well, Tyler is a co-founder of the
business, so they uh gave us how about
some cheap fees. All right. Didn't
charge us a lot for the for the product.
But I I think um you know what what we
think the market wants is a native
Bitcoin business founded by
technologists. You know, you should ask
Paulo and and bring up his founding
stories because Paulo and I are both
CEOs now, but before we were CEOs, we
were engineers. Nice. We were
contributors to the Bitcoin protocol. We
had built stuff with our bare hands. And
so it's founded with technology
background, little cippher punk
attitude. We hear a lot about how Wall
Street has arrived on Bitcoin with IBIT
and Larry Frink. We think of 21 as
Bitcoin has arrived on Wall Street and
we are showing up in our hoodies on Wall
Street. Um, and we know how to custody
Bitcoin ourselves. We know how to do
proof of reserves. We are Bitcoiners.
And so we think the capital markets in
America, they want a public Bitcoin
equity that they can trust, that they
can understand, and that they know is an
expert in the asset class. And so for
us, we think proof of reserves is a
small but very meaningful step for us to
be able to convey that to the market
that, you know, we didn't just get into
Bitcoin or we're not pivoting from
something else. Paulo and I have been in
this game for over a decade and know we
very much know what we're doing. I
really wanted to ask you about
stablecoin, but
now I want to ask you about your hoodie
because
financial institutions, everybody,
everybody dressed like this. You guys
are great, by the way. Well, thank you.
Thank you. Um, and I assume they're much
older. So, when you walk into a room,
they're going to be like, "Who are you?"
Yeah. Well, um I think uh to me, Bitcoin
is disrupting far more than just
financial markets. Um
and for me personally,
uh I want to bring to the world
authenticity,
transparency. I think, you know, nobody
wants another old white bald guy in a
blue suit and Louis Vuitton sneakers
trying to convince you of a version of
the world that you know in your heart is
wrong. I think the world is sick of
that. And to be honest, everything that
you see around you was invented and made
by someone no greater than you. And
I want to bring as a CEO and someone
with a platform, I want to bring a sense
of relatability and humanize this asset
class and the fact that, you know, I'm
I'm just a dude and we all are. And
notion that there are some more
important people than others that are in
the White House that decide how much
money should be worth to all of us is a
bunch of crap. And for some reason,
people have been afraid to say that. And
so for good or for bad, um I've really
dedicated my voice and my style to just
be me. Um because I think it's important
and I think the world is in desperate
demand for something authentic that they
can understand and relate to. I love
this. Your your your hoodie looks
authentic. Yes. Is that your own line or
is that somebody else's? No, I do have
uh we're giving away some hoodies. Uh
we're giving away some Hottle hoodies
actually. Uh, so I'll make sure you guys
get some. But next conference, we'll
have to wear hoodies from Abberro and
Fitch. So much more comfortable. My god.
Yeah. I think and you know the you know
people definitely have their comments
and such, but again I think um like my
empty closet for example. Oh yes about
that. The empty closet to me it was an
accident. Total accident and turned into
a meme on the internet like all great
inventions. But to me, it was so
powerful because on my channel where
this guy's closet's bigger than my
house. But you know what I what I think
what I think the important the reason I
kept it is I think the fact that
someone's working on Bitcoin in the
heart of a hyper financialized American
closet where you're incented to
overconume, right? the American
consumer. The job of the American
consumer is to support the world's
factory, which is China, which is all
these other trade partners. They export
stuff into our country, and our job is
to just consume it. And so, the fact
that someone had a closet full of Gucci
and Louis and shoes and this or that
goes to show the state of America that
we're in. This world reserve currency,
piles and piles of deficits, hyper
financialized, overconumption version of
America. So, I'm going to sit right in
the heart of the most materialistic
overconumption background and work on
open- source software in a hoodie. And
that message, I think, speaks more than
I could ever put into words. So, these
are the type of things that aren't
software, they aren't products, but I do
think Bitcoin helps um revolutionize and
educate and message. And so, I try and
channel a lot of that uh in who I am.
And I hope that more CEOs and
politicians, we get back to proof of
work and and being vulnerable, authentic
humans.
Let's try to be authentic humans,
everybody. Yes. All right. Thank you
very much, Jack. Appreciate it. Thank
you. Does that mean um you can't put any
clothes in your closet? It has to remain
empty. Yeah. Well, so my girlfriend just
moved in and we share the other closet.
Okay. So, it's going to stay empty until
one day I'll turn it into like a golf
simulator or something. It's already
your podcast studio. Yeah, it works. It
works. Thanks, Jack. Yeah, thank you
guys. All right. Thank you.